<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>low carb on Recipes</title><link>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/tags/low-carb/</link><description>Recent content in low carb on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 12:48:16 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/tags/low-carb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Curried Cauliflower Soup</title><link>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/cauliflower-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 12:48:16 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/cauliflower-soup/</guid><description>Full of flavor and can be adapted to a vegan dish.
Prep Cook Serves 30 min 15 min 4-6 Ingredients 1/2 cup raw cashews 3/4 cup water 2 tsp coconut oil 1 large onion, diced 1 large cauliflower head, cut into 1 inch pieces 1 can coconut milk 3 tbsp curry powder 1 tsp ground turmeric 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp sugar 1/4 tsp ground cinnamoon salt to taste (optional, bacon bits for decoration, heavy cream, 1 yellow potato) Steps Put the cashews in a blender and blend on high until finely ground.</description></item><item><title>Rouladen (stuffed beef rolls)</title><link>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/rouladen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 12:48:16 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/rouladen/</guid><description>A recipe my mom tought me when I was a teenager. It is a traditional German dish accompanied by potatoe dumplings or Spaetzle and red cabbage.
Prep Cook Serves 30 min 2 hr 8 Ingredients For the meet:
8 thin slices of top round beef (1/4 in thick and roughly 6X10 in in size) yellow mustard 8 slices bacon 8 pickles 1 large onion salt and pepper For the gravy:</description></item><item><title>Curry-Dates Dip</title><link>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/curry-dattel-dip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 09:03:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/curry-dattel-dip/</guid><description>Super yummy for breakfast or on a charcuterie board
Prep Mix Yields 5 min 1 min 1 jelly jar Ingredients 150 g pitted dates 2 garlic cloves 200 g Garlic Alouette 100 g sour cream 2 teaspon curry powder ¼ - ½ TL cayenne pepper 1 dash salt and pepper to taste Steps Cut dates in half and put in a high speed blender Add garlic, cheese, and sour cream to the blender and mix until semi smooth Now add the curry, peppers and salt and blend again.</description></item><item><title>Granola (Olive Oil and Maple)</title><link>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/granola/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 09:03:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/granola/</guid><description>Very crunchy and nutty snack enjoyed with milk or just like that
Prep Bake Yields 10 min 45 min 6-7 mason jars Ingredients 6 cups old fashioned oats 2 cups raw pumpkin seeds 2 cups raw sunflower seeds 1 cup flax seeds 2 cups unsweetened coconut chips (the large ones from Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s) 3 cups raw pecans 3 cups raw or dry roasted hazelnuts 2 cup maple syrup 2 cup packed brown sugar 1 cup extra virgin olive oil 1 Tbsp Maldon Salt flaked (use half if using regular salt) Steps In a super big bowl (I am using the baby tub) mix all the nuts and seeds thoroughly.</description></item><item><title>Marzipan (almond paste)</title><link>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/marzipan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 09:03:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/marzipan/</guid><description>Homemade Marzipan to enjoy raw or for baking
Prep Store Yields 10 min 2-3 weeks 400 g Ingredients 250 g blanched almond flour (Costco has the best deal) 150 g powdered sugar 4 ½ tbsp (60 ml) water 1 ½ tsp almond extract (optional but very recommended) 1 tsp rose water food grade (optional) Steps Mix the almond flour and powdered sugar in a food processor or kitchen aid with the kneading hook Add the water, almond extract, and rose water (optional) and pulse a couple of times until the dough holds together and forms a ball.</description></item><item><title>Marzipanhörnchen (marzipan cookies)</title><link>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/marzipanhoernchen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 09:03:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/marzipanhoernchen/</guid><description>Classic German almond cookie - a family favorite
Prep Bake Serves 10 min 15-20 min 20-24 cookies Ingredients 400 g marzipan dough (buy at Fred Meyer or homemade (see here: Almond paste) 150 g powdered sugar 2 egg whites (ca. 50g) 70 g ground almonds 200 g sliced almonds 200 g tempered chocolade for glazing 20 ml Amaretto or Rum Steps Cut up the marzipan into small cubes With a kitchen mixer mix powdered sugar, ground almonds, amaretto and egg whites to a smooth (very sticky) dough Let rest in fridge for 15-30 min (easier to form the dough when chilled) Preheat oven to 350F (325 convection) Put the sliced almonds on a large plate with a rim (to roll the cookies in) Cut the dough into 40g portions and roll them on the almond filled plate into crecents (easier with slightly wet hands because of super sticky dough).</description></item><item><title>Mouse Au Chocolate</title><link>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/choc-mousse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 09:03:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/choc-mousse/</guid><description>Super quick and sugar free chocolate mousse.
Prep Chill Serves 10 min 30 min 4-6 Ingredients 1.5 cup heavy whipping cream 4 tbps heavy whipping cream 1/4 cup cocoa powder 25 g 100% cocoa baking chocolate 2 tbsp sweetener, I like purevia dark chocolate chunks, or dark baking chocolate in slivers for decoration Steps Whip heavy cream until fully thinkened and then add sweetener, vanilla and cocoa.</description></item><item><title>Teddy's sourdough bread (Mischbrot))</title><link>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/teddys-mischbrot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 09:03:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/teddys-mischbrot/</guid><description>This is the most authentic German sourdough rye bread with 50% rye, 25% whole wheat, 25% white wheat. Has a crunchy crust and is even more delicious with added seeds like pumpking, flax or sunflower.It requires a sourdough starter.
Prep Rest Bake 10 min 20-22 hours 1 hour Ingredients To prep your sourdough:
1st step: (5 hours resting, 25°C/76°F)</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Cake (Low Carb)</title><link>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/chocolate-cake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/chocolate-cake/</guid><description>Super easy low carb chocolate cake, ideal as basis for black forest cake and other layer cakes.
Prep Bake Serves 10 min 15-20 min 1 8x12 pan Ingredients 1/3 cup milk 3 eggs 1 tbsp Vanilla extract 1.5 cups almond flour 0.5 cup coconut flour 1/4 cup cocoa powder 1 pinch salt 1/3 cup granulated sugar substitute 2.</description></item><item><title>Plum Cake (Low Carb)</title><link>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/pflaumen-kuchen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://knusperflocky.github.io/recipes/posts/pflaumen-kuchen/</guid><description>Low carb version of plum cobbler.
Prep Bake Serves 30 min 25-30 min 1 8x12 pan Ingredients 1/2 stick butter, softened 3/4 cup milk 3 egg 1 tbsp Vanilla extract 1 tsp Almond extract 1.5 cups almond flour 0.5 cup coconut flour 1/4 tsp xantam gum 1 pinch salt 1/2 cup granulated sugar substitute 2 tsp baking poweder 20-25 plums (depending on size, I used italian prunes in recipe) 1 cup slivered almonds (or chopped) Steps Mix very soft butter with sweetener, until smooth.</description></item></channel></rss>